welcome back to a push and under 3
minutes no time for intros let's get
into it all right it is the 1840s and
Americans are looking West this idea
that Americans deserve and are destined
to expand across the entire continent
that is something known and called
Manifest Destiny and it was very popular
in this time period so the big question
is why why did Americans think they were
destined to expand well simply because
land equal opportunity the West had
resources open land and the chance to
get rich Farmers saw fertile soil miners
Chase gold and religious groups like The
Mormons just wanted to be left alone in
Utah and if you want a city to blame on
that you can look at Salt Lake City so
people just started packing up and
heading west and when I say heading west
I mean thousands of settlers risking
their lives on Trails like the Oregon
Trail imagine walking 2,000 Mi losing
half of your wagon fighting off dentry
and all you get in the end is a nice
view but hey for many it was actually
worth it and that leads to the one image
that will always forever be used to
Define manifest destiny I mean look at
that angel it's as if these people were
meant to expand West or at least that's
what they thought at the time and the
funny part is the government wanted in
on the expansion too to help settlers
they passed the Homestead Act basically
handing out free land that is if you
could survive on it and the Pacific
Railroad Act which helped build
railroads across the country this made
it way easier to move west but the US
wasn't just looking West they were
looking transnational Americans wanted
more trade with Asia and in classic us
fashion they weren't exactly subtle
about it the Treaty of I'm not even
going to try and pronounce that opened
up trade with China and the Treaty of
Kagawa forced Japan to open its ports to
American ships I know I've said a
million times that expansion Westward
would cause the Civil War but before the
Civil War it will actually cause a
revolution and another War but that is a
next video Problem on the screen now are
some AP style questions for this topic
pause
now I'll put the answers on the screen
now
I will see you in the next one